A Finding Aid to the Anna Coleman Ladd Papers, 1881-1950, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Anna Coleman Ladd papers
1881-1950
Archives of American Art
Ladd, Anna Coleman, 1878-1939 (sculptor)
AAA.laddanna
Archival Resource Key
4.26 Linear feet
The papers of sculptor Anna Coleman Ladd measure 4.26 linear feet, date from 1881-1950, and document the career of sculptor Anna Coleman Ladd. Found within the papers are biographical material, letters, diaries, financial material, notes and writings, art work, a file concerning the American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks, scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Anna Coleman Ladd papers were donated in 1991 by William Terry on behalf of Robert Edwards, a friend of Anna Coleman Ladd.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical/Historical note
Born in 1878 in Philadelphia to John and Mary Watts, Anna Coleman Ladd (née Watts) was educated in private schools and Europe. She also studied in America under Charles Grafly.
She moved to Boston in 1905 and married Boston pediatrician Maynard Ladd with whom she had two daughters, Gabriella May Ladd and Vernon Abbott Ladd. Working in her studio on Clarendon Street, Ladd became one of the city's most prolific sculptors, creating fountain pieces, portrait busts, memorials, and reliefs in addition to authoring two novels, Hieronymus Rides in 1912, and The Candid Adventurer in 1913.
Between 1907 and 1915, Ladd had solo exhibitions at the Gorham Gallery in New York, the Corcoran Gallery in Washington, D.C., and the Pennsylvania Academy in Philadelphia. She was also invited to exhibit her bronzes at the Panama Pacific Exposition in San Francisco. In 1914 she executed a bronze statuette of Eleanora Duse for which the actress posed, and later completed portrait busts of Anna Pavlova and Ethel Barrimore.
In late 1917 in Paris, Ladd founded the American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks to provide cosmetic masks to be worn by men who had been badly disfigured in World War I. Her services earned her the Légion d'Honneur Crois de Chevalier and the Serbian Order of Saint Sava.
For many years, Ladd maintained a summer studio "Arden" at Beverly Farms in Manchester, Massachusetts. In 1923, she received an honorary degree of Master of Arts from Tufts College.
Anna Coleman Ladd died June 3, 1939 in Santa Barbara, California.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of sculptor Anna Coleman Ladd measure 4.26 linear feet, date from 1881-1950, and document the career of sculptor Anna Coleman Ladd. Found within the papers are biographical material, letters, diaries, financial material, notes and writings, art work, a file concerning the American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks, scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs.
Biographical materials are scattered and include calling cards, biographical sketches notes, and certificates.
Correspondence includes letters written to Anna Coleman Ladd from various family members, friends, and colleagues. Notable correspodents include William Aldrich, Gabriella Fabbricotti, Isabella Stewart Gardner, Natalie Hays Hammond, and Jessie Eldridge Southwick.
Diaries are daily diaries dating from 1903-1905 and from 1911-1912. Each diary includes short descriptions of Ladd's days.
Financial materials include receipts, stock certificates, travel materials, lists, and an account book for Dr. Maynard Ladd.
Writings and notes consists of notebooks, lists of works of art, inventories, manuscripts by Ladd and by others.
Artworks include two sketchbooks, loose drawings, and a plaster relief by Ladd as well as several sketches by others.
American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks files include correspondence, writings, a scrapbook, printed materials, and photographs. Materials concern portrait masks used to disguise the disfigured faces of World War I veterans.
Scrapbooks consists of three scrapbooks containing photographs, printed materials, and writings.
Printed materials include clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs for Ladd's works, books and booklets, and posters, some of which are French World War I propaganda.
Photographs include photographs of Anna Coleman Ladd with her works of art and in the studio, Dr. Maynard Ladd, friends, family, colleagues, and works of sculpture.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 10 series. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1910-1950 (Box 1; 4 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1895-1937 (Box 1-2; 1.1 linear feet)
Series 3: Diaries, 1903-1912 (Box 2; 2 folders)
Series 4: Financial Material, 1899-1934 (Box 2; 6 folders)
Series 5: Writings and Notes, 1888-1949 (Box 2, 6, OV 7; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 6: Artwork, 1901-1928 (Box 2, 6, OV 7; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 7: American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks File, 1914-1925 (Box 2-3, 6; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 8: Scrapbooks, 1900-1940 (Box 3; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 9: Printed Material, 1889-1942 (Box 3, 6, OV 7; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 10: Photographs, 1881-1932 (Box 4-6, MGP 1; 0.8 linear feet)
Existence and Location of Copies
The collection was digitized in 2014 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website.
Authors -- Massachusetts -- Boston; Sculptors -- Massachusetts -- Boston; Women artists; Women sculptors; Women authors; Works of art; Portrait sculpture; Architectural sculpture; Artists' studios -- Photographs; Diaries; Drawings; Sketchbooks; Photographs; Sketches; Scrapbooks; World War, 1914-1918; Aldrich, William; Southwick, Jessie Eldridge; Hammond, Natalie Hays, 1905-; American Red Cross. Studio for Portrait Masks (Paris, France); Gardner, Isabella Stewart, 1840-1924; Fabbricotti, Gabriella
- Biographical Material, circa 1905-1950; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 4 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes biographical and genealogical notes for Anna Coleman Ladd and the Ladd family, including an application to the WPA. There are also membership and award certificates.
  Arrangement note
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Calling Cards, circa 1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Sketches, 1930-1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Genealogical Notes, circa 1910-circa 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Certificates, 1910-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1895-1937; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.1 Linear feet Box 1-2
  Letters are primarily from family members and friends including Countess Nora Balzani, Dr. Bindo de Vecchio, and painter Gabriella Fabbricotti. There are a few letters each from colleagues Emil Ahlborn, William Aldrich, Frances F. Brundage, Ralph Adams Cram, Willard Cummings, John Ettl, Isabella Stewart Gardner, Charles Grafly, Lilian Westcott Hale, Philip Leslie Hale, Natalie Hays Hammond, J. Scott Hartley, Malvina Hoffman, Anna Vaughn Hyatt, Leila Mechlin, Violet Oakley, Albin Polasek, Bertha Potter, Janet Scudder, Thomas Mott Shaw, Lorado Taft, and Rosamond Tudor. There are also letters from activists Elisabeth Achelis, Florence Peshine Eagleton, and Gabrielle Enthoven, actors Julie Opp Faversham, William Faversham, Frances Starr, and Gilda Varesi, composer Louisa P. Loring, dancers Beate Bolm, Michio Ito, and Anna Pavolva, and writers James Bryce, Maud Howe Elliott, Eirene Mungo-Park, Romain Rolland, Porter Sargent, Jessie Eldridge Southwick, and Riccardo Tramontano.
  Researchers should note that some correspondence is unsigned or illegible.
  Undated letters are arranged in alphabetical order and are found at the beginning of the series. The bulk of the correspondence is arranged chronologically.
  - Unidentified Correspondents and Fragments, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - First Names A-B, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - First Names C-G, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - First Names H-L, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - First Names M, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - First Names N, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - First Names P-Z, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Surnames A, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Surnames B, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Surnames C, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Surnames D-E, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Surnames F-G, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Surnames H, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Surnames I-K, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Surnames L, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Surnames M, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Surnames N-R, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Surnames S, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Surnames T-Z, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Anna Coleman Watts Ladd, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
    (to her children, husband, and drafts to friends)
  - Gabrielle Ladd, circa 1920-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Maynard Ladd, circa 1900-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Vernon Abbott Ladd, circa 1920-circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letters, 1895-1896; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Scope and Contents
    Missing Title
    Brown, Henry Hobart
  - Letters, 1897-1898; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Tom (maybe Thomas Mott Shaw) Trevelyn, Madeline
  - Letters, 1899; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Merrill, George Grenville
    Tom (maybe Thomas Mott Shaw)
  - Letters, 1900; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Baldwin, Abraham Rosencrans
    Ladd, Maynard
  - Letters, 1901; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Greene, Rosalind and Henry Copley
  - Letters, 1902; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Fabbricotti, Gabriella
  - Letters, 1903 Jan-May; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Balzani, Nora
  - Letters, 1903 Jun-Dec; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
    de Vecchio, Bindo
  - Letters, 1904 Jan-May; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Letters, 1904 Jun; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Letters, 1904 Jul; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Watts, John
    Bryce, James
    MacMillan, Frederick
  - Letters, 1904 Aug; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Roosevelt, George
  - Letters, 1904 Sep; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Girolemo, F.
  - Letters, 1904 Oct; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Balzani, I.
  - Letters, 1904 Nov-Dec; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letters, 1905 Jan-Apr; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Letters, 1905 May; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Letters, 1905 Jun; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Mungo-Park, Eirene
    A., Nina
    Gentili (?), Ida
    Tejan (?), Bianca Bardo
    Potter, Bertha
  - Letters, 1905 Jul-Dec; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Perry, Blinn
    de Bellegarde, Nina
  - Letters, 1906; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Poole, Lavore
    Leroy, E.
    del Buono, Albert
  - Letters, 1907; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Holt, Henry
    Smith, Gertrude Robinson
  - Letters, 1908; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Sargent, Porter
    Fray, Ronald
    Mechlin, Leila
    French, W.M.R.
  - Letters, 1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Taft, Lorado
    Coolidge, J.R. Jr.
    Malcolm, Victoria
    Grafly, Charles
  - Letters, 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Holt, Roland
  - Letters, 1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Macbeth, Robert Walker
    Brunetti, Jose
    Polasek, Albin
    Trask, John E.D.
    Borghese, Ann
    Scudder, Janet
    Phillips, Caroline Drayton
    Aldrich, William
  - Letters, 1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Zanelli, Angelo
    McKay, Helen
    Hale, Philip L.
    Ricker, Nettie M.
    Hartley, J. Scott
    Faversham, Julie Opp
    Faversham, William
  - Letters, 1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Tucker, Caroline
  - Letters, 1914; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Howland, Esther
  - Letters, 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Powell, F.C.
    Kingston, Gertrude
  - Letters, 1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Southwick, Jessie Eldridge
    Boynton Monks
    Heard, Ralph Prescott
    Eggers, George W.
  - Letters, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Tramontano, Riccardo
    Tarbell, Ida
    Bolm, Beate
    Barttell, Mary F.
  - Letters, 1918-1919; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Miller, E. Achelis
    Bochman, Mrs. Charles
    Oakley, Violet
  - Letters, 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Brundage, Frances F.
    Forbes, Allan
    Gardner, Isabella Stewart
    Rollins, Mabel
    Barnard, George Grey
    Kelsey, Albert
    Sturgis, R. Clipston
    Harshe, Robert
  - Letters, 1921-1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Blake, William
  - Letters, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Tudor, Rosamond
    Pavlova, Anna
  - Letters, 1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Hayward, Alfred
    Megrew, Louise G.
  - Letters, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letters, 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Letters, 1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Kirk, Henry
    MacAusland, Andrew
    Minahan, Katharine
    Angel, John
    Achelis, Elisabeth
    Scarborough, Dorothy
  - Letters, 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Clough, Clarence
    Picot, Colonel
    Rollard, Romain
  - Letters, 1930-1931; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
    de Marco, Etta de Vite
    McKenzie, R. Tait
    Shaw, Louis
  - Letters, 1932; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Williamson, J.
    Pollak-Ottendorff, Emil
    Fiske, Claire
  - Letters, 1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Morgan, Emily
    Frary, William
  - Letters, 1934-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Letters, 1936-1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Diaries, 1903-1912; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders Box 2
  The diaries contain brief annotations describing Ladd's daily activities. The diary dated 1903-1905 also contains a list of relief sculptures. The other diary has a hand-worked suede cover, and primarily annotates daily activities in 1911. There is also a page of annotations describing activities dating from January 20 to 27, 1912, with an additional page listing names.
  This series has been partially scanned. The diary dating from 1903-1905 has not been scanned due to the fragility of the document.
  - Diary, 1903-1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Diary, 1911-1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Financial Material, 1899-1934; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 6 Folders Box 2
  Financial material consists of receipts for the sale of art work and for travel, stock certificates for the Alliance Oil Company, and a promissory note and account book relating to Maynard Ladd's medical practice.
  - Promissory Note from Maynard Ladd, 1899; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Travel Receipts, 1903-1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Travel Receipts, 1911-1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Sales Lists and Receipts for Art Work, 1911-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Stock Certificates for the Alliance Oil Company, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Accounts Book for Dr. Maynard Ladd, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Notes and Writings, 1888-1949; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 2, 6, OV 7
  This series consists of notebooks and manuscripts written by Anna Coleman Ladd and by others, some of which are illustrated by Ladd. Notebook 1 primarily contains lists of mythological and allegorical characters. Notebook 2 contains historical notes, listings of Italian authors and painters, poems, clippings, anatomical drawings, and an illustrated letter. Notebook 3 contains notes from a class in composition. Notebook 4 contains lists of friends' names and poetry.
  The guest register contains autographs of William Aldrich, Senator Albert J. Beveridge, Gabriella Fabbricotti, Isabella Stewart Gardner, Philip Leslie Hale, John Hays Hammond, Marie Danforth Page, Agnes Repplier, John Singer Sargent, Frances Starr. There are two small hand-made books by Anna Coleman Watts and Gabriella Fabbricotta. Miscellaneous poems include the poem "Hymn for Easter" by Dorothy Grafly.
  - Notebook 1, circa 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Notebook 2, circa 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Notebook 2, circa 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Notebook 3, 1899; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Notebook 4, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Guest Register, 1912-1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Lists of Guests, circa 1910-1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Lists of Sculpture by Anna Coleman Ladd, circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - List of Sitters for Portraits, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Lists of Photographs, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Notes for Blue Prints and Blue Prints, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6 and OV 7
  - Inventories of Art Work and Miscellaneous Possessions, 1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Lecture about Being a Sculptor, circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Act IV of an Unidentified Play, circa 1910s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Hidden Gardens, circa 1910s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - The Young Prince, 1888; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Part I, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 1, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 2-4, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 5-7, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 8-10, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 13, 17-18, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 20-23, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 24-29, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 30, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 33, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 34, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Chapter 37-38, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Drawings, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Hieronymus Rides, Galleys, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - The Strong: Drama in Four Acts, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - The Strong: Drama in Four Acts, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - The Strong: Drama in Four Acts, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Miscellaneous Writings with Illustrations, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Writings by Anna Coleman Ladd, circa 1900-circa 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Hand-Made Booklet The Hangman's Daughter, by Gabriella Fabbricotti, circa 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous Poems by Others, 1902-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Oversized Notes and Blue Prints for Miscellaneous Sculpture Projects, 1923-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 2, F32
  - Oversized Blue Prints for Michael J. Cadigan Post 46 Stele, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 7)
- Artwork, 1901-1928; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 2, 6, OV 7
  Art work consists of sketchbooks, drawings, and a small plaster relief sculpture by Anna Coleman Ladd. Art work by others includes a drawing of Mademoiselle Monnier by E. Briant, a watercolor sketch by E. Hunter, and a cut-out silhouette of a woman.
  - Sketchbook 1, circa 1900-circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Sketchbook 2, 1902; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Drawings by Anna Coleman Ladd, 1902-1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Drawings by Anna Coleman Ladd, 1902-1905; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Art Work by Others, 1901-1928; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Plaster Relief Sculpture by Anna Coleman Ladd, circa 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 64)
    Oversized material housed in Box 6
  - Oversized Drawings and Oversized Relief Sculpture, circa 1910; Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 2, Folder 62, 64
  - Oversized Drawings, Tracings, circa 1920s-circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 7)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 2, Folder 62
- American Red Cross Studio for Portrait-Masks File, 1914-1925; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 0.4 Linear feet Box 2-3, 6
  This series contains material relating to Ladd's services aiding soldiers badly disfigured during World War I. Ladd established a studio in Paris in which she fashioned cosmetic masks to be worn by soldiers with terrible facial wounds. The notes and writings include a small notebook of price lists for sculptures. The scrapbook contains letters, clippings, and photographs of Maynard Ladd in the trenches, and of disfigured soldiers both with and without their masks.
  - Letters, 1919-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Notes and Writings, circa 1914-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Scrapbook, 1914-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Scrapbook, 1914-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Scrapbook, 1914-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Scrapbook, 1914-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Scrapbook, 1914-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Scrapbook, 1914-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Scrapbook, 1914-1933; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Printed Material, 1916-1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, 1914-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Photographs, circa 1920s-circa 1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 6)
    Oversized material scanned with Box 3, F2
- Scrapbooks, 1900-1940; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 0.3 Linear feet Box 3
  Scrapbook 1 primarily contains photographs, clippings, and postcards showing works of art and architecture. Scrapbook 2 contains photographs of Ladd and her work, notes and writings, and clippings. Scrapbook 3 contains photographs of art work, a writing entitled "Jesus and the Sleeping Child," a booklet, and clippings.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1900; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1913-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1913-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1913-1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)